TOBIAS CANAVESI

Data Scientist, PhD

ntobiascanavesi



PERSONAL PROFILE

I consider myself in love with mathematics and the Universe. I have a bachelor degree in Astronomy and I'm in the last month of my Ph.D. in theoretical physics. I also like technology (particularly Artificial Intelligence). I did Data Science courses and i have experience working in important projects across various industries. I'm a versatile person, capable of adapting to any task or problem to solve. I enjoy working with people from different areas because i think that multidisciplinary collaboration is key to the advancement of society. Some of my hobbies are playing and collecting retro games, programming, reading, and thinking about the future.

ACTUAL POSITION

Senior Data Scientist Hevday

- Movember 2021 Ongoing
- **Q** United States, Remotely
- Create analytical solutions in SQL and Python to solve different needs.
- Elevate forecasting capabilities and accuracy by utilizing AI techniques.

Postgraduate professor University of Buenos Aires

- May 2022 Ongoing
- Postgraduate professor at the School of Engineering of the University of Buenos Aires, teaching the course Machine Learning I for the Artificial Intelligence Specialization Course (CEIA).

Postgraduate Assistant

Faculty of astronomical and geophysical sciences

- August 2018 Ongoing
- ♦ La Plata, Argentina
- Chief of Practical Studies of modern physics subject of the astronomy degree.

LANGUAGES

MY LIFE PHILOSOPHY

"Every problem has a solution, even if the solution is in another problem."

SKILLS



Work in group

Ability to work in a group, either leading or being part of it



Programming

Programming in different languages mainly in Python and Mathematica.



Data Science Skills

Data wrangling, Data Visualization, ability to understand a problem in depth in order to be able to use the appropriate machine learning and deep learning tools. Segmentation, forecasting, regression and classification.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Wolfram
- SQL
- Problem solving skills
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Cloud

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Theoretical Physics National University of La Plata

April 2018 - February 2023

Data Science

Digital House

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

Deep Learning Specialization

Deep Learning AI

🛗 Jan 2022 - No expiration date

PREVIOUS POSITION

Specialist Data Scientist

Accenture

Mov 2021 - Dec 2022

Puenos Aires, Argentina

 Manage, architect and analyze big data in order to build data driven business insights and high impact data models to generate significant business value. Create models and processes to collect, distill and interpret data with a view to aid better, more informed decision making.

SELECT EXPERIENCE

Demand Forecasting Airline Company (Chile)

2022 - Ongoing

- Design, implementation and evaluation of machine learning models for time series forecasting.
- Forecast performance analysis comparing ML and time series models.
- Study on price elasticity of demand.

Simulation - Optimization

Mining Industry (Canada)

2022

- Part of the team in charge of creating a simulation and optimization model for water treatment. (Databricks + Azure)
- Agile project management (Azure DevOps).

Optimization

Mining Industry (Chile)

2022

• Creation of a water use optimization model. (Databricks + Azure)

Segmentation - Clustering

E-Commerce (LATAM)

₩ 2022

- Definition of metrics and algorithms for retraining clustering models
- Application of statistics to understand a better application of promotions.

Demand Forecasting

Drinks company (Chile)

⊞ 2021

- Design, implementation and evaluation of machine learning models for time series forecasting. (AWS - Sagemaker)
- Forecast performance analysis comparing ML and time series models. (AWS Sagemaker)

Instructor of the Wolfram Summer School 2021 Wolfram Research (United States)

2021

• Working as a mentor at the Wolfram 2021 summer school. https://education.wolfram.com/summer-school

CERTIFICATIONS

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Neural Networks and Deep Learning Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Convolutional Neural Networks Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Sequence Models

Deep Learning AI

🛗 Jun 2022 - No expiration date

Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python

Deep Learning AI

Introduction to Machine Learning in Production

Deep Learning AI

₩ Jul 2022 - No expiration date

AWARDS

Thank you for being an Al Hero - Client Value Creation

Accenture

₩ Aug 2022

PUBLISHED RESEARCH

Scalar correlators and normal modes in holographic neutron stars

Classical and Quantum Gravity

2022

Thermodynamic instabilities in holographic neutron stars at finite temperature

Classical and Quantum Gravity

∰ 2020